Mohammed Magdy Ismael

Senior Frontend Engineer

Address Cairo, Egypt (willing to relocate)

Phone +201066202453

+201101230192

Email m.magdy.isl@gmail.com

GitHub github.com/mohammedmagdyismael
LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/mohammedmagdyismael
CodePen codepen.io/mohammedmagdyismael

Professional Summary

Energetic and team-oriented frontend software engineer with 6 years of work experience. Highly-skilled in architecting and building React web apps and packages.

As a team tech owner in a multinational company, I believe in culture diversity, proactivity and decision making with the flexibility of discussion so we can lead our potential to the optimum goal.

A very fast self-learner, and extremely eager to learn, I really enjoy challenges that push my limits where I can reach my best, creating both beautiful, and creative work, fulfilling my deep interest in front-end web development.

I believe in the T model, in which I have to have a background about every developing domain other than frontend to have a wide scale of knowledge and easy discussing with other domains members.

Technical Skills

SSR	JSON	Jira	SOLID
Redux	React Testing	Illustrator	OOP
NodeJS	TDD	Photoshop	Azure DevOps
ExpressJS	Jest	Figma	Jenkins
TypeScript	Unit test	Firebase	SDLC
REST	Git	Google Optimize	NPM
MongoDB	Lerna	Mixpanel	Linux
SQL	Monorepo	Raygun	Webpack
GraphQL	Agile	AWS	Data Structure
React Native	SCRUM	CDN	Algorithms
	Redux NodeJS ExpressJS TypeScript REST MongoDB SQL GraphQL	Redux React Testing NodeJS TDD ExpressJS Jest TypeScript Unit test REST Git MongoDB Lerna SQL Monorepo GraphQL Agile	ReduxReact TestingIllustratorNodeJSTDDPhotoshopExpressJSJestFigmaTypeScriptUnit testFirebaseRESTGitGoogle OptimizeMongoDBLernaMixpanelSQLMonorepoRaygunGraphQLAgileAWS

Work Experience

Vezeeta, Cairo - Egypt

Senior Frontend Engineer Level I, 01/2019 - Present

- Proiects:
 - 1. Vezeeta Payment Portal Squad (Developer)
 - 2. Vezeeta Offers Squad (Developer) www.vezeeta.com/en/offers
 - 3. Vezeeta/HIS integration (Developer)
 - 4. Vezeeta Practice Management System (Tech. Owner and Developer)
- Act as squad technical owner, responsible for Collaboration with technical teams and product managers to collect requirements, identify tasks, align estimates, follow up with agile based meetings with SCRUM / Kanban methodologies to meet production deadlines.
- Worked with both Client and server-side applications
- Manage the ability to lead junior and mid-level engineers, help to improve their coding skills via code review meetings, technical discussion meetings to reach the best practices.
- Communicating with both Operation and R&D teams to optimize the performance of current web application on both hands, Technical performance and User Experience.
- Following UI styling good practice to enhance application responsivity.
- Creating fully customized UI components follows Vezeeta experience.
- Introducing Raygun as a bug tracer to inspect any production-based issues.

- Improvise performance and scalability of the system after identifying the root cause for the most complex issues and develop efficient and permanent technical solutions.
- Using Azure DevOps to build a CI/CD pipeline for the frontend components to create a seamless deployment process without manual work.
- Responsible for developing Vezeeta Practice Management System (B2B) enhancing Clinics and Entities experience to follow Patient details (Bookings, Patient Profile, Financial Reporting for the entity, ...)
- Integrating projects with Firebase (Remote Config) implementing Feature flags.
- Increase the loading and interactivity performance of the user with pages
- Increase engagement of the users with the web application by 30% per month, measured by event trackers.
- Developing with Test Driven Developing using for the components by writing unit tests using Jest.
- Maintain security and the privacy means to keep the user info through his journey on the web application.
- Achieving 8 coding hours per day, you can check real statistics through my GitHub account
- Implemented responsive website for Vezeeta Offers Product www.vezeeta.com/en/offers
- Achieving about 18500 books in Egypt and KSA since launching, bounce rate 56% in KSA and Egypt, conversion rate about 4.94% in Egypt.
- Increase bounce rate on Practice Management project to +15% (tracked with Mixpanel)

DevisionX, Cairo - Egypt

Frontend Engineer, 07/2017 - 07/2018

 Developing react web apps for machine learning systems to detect National ID info using CNN trained model to extract the info visually from photo using TensorFlow.

Education

B.Sc. in Computers & Systems Engineering, Mansoura University, Mansoura (2014)

Languages

Arabic (Mother Language) English (Professional) French (Elementary Level)

Personal Information

Birthdate: 23 January 1992

Military Status: Completed (04/2017)

Marital Status: Single

Activities

- ASME (American Society of Mechanical Engineers)
- student conference committee chair- Mansoura Section
- ROV Competition (2012,2013 Image & Video Processing and Control)
- Mine Sweepers Competition (GUC & IEEE) (Controlling Quad-Copter) (2014 Team Supervisor)
- IEARN Active member (2006-2010)
- SIFE (Enactus) Mansoura member (2010-2011)
- ROBOTRICKS Faculty team for Engineering Activities (2012-2013)
- Scientific Community of Computer and Control Department (2012)
- IRC International Competition (2013 Qualifications)
- Machine Vision Instructor